ASHLYN LANAVILLE

Software Engineer

(206) 833.7852 · <u>ashlyn@downing.us</u> · Seattle, WA · ashlyn-lanaville-portfolio.netlify.app/ · www.linkedin.com/in/ashlynlanaville/ · github.com/ashlynl00

I am a detail-driven **software engineer** that has a passion for solving complex front-end and back-end technologies. With about 4 years of experience leading groups of people in various organizations, I have a strong foundation in communication and working with a team to solve a challenge. I value developing creative and concise solutions that can make an impact on those around me and am looking for opportunities to continue to develop better and more efficient web technologies.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS | **Libraries and Frameworks** - Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, React.js, EJS, Bcrypt **Database** - MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM | **Other** - RESTful Routing JSON, Heroku, Git/Github, VSCode, Command Line Interface, API's, JSON, Responsive Web Design

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

February 2022 - Present

Neighborly - Mern Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, React)

- Independently designed a social-based app for people who want to connect with their neighborhood communities and meet people in their area.
- Incorporated MongoDB, Express.js, React, and Node.js to develop a Mern application with full CRUD capability.
- Employed React components to render information from a local API depending on user authorization.

Human Resources - Full-Stack (Express.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js), Javascript, CSS

- Collaborated with a team to implement RESTful routes and create a full CRUD application to build a space for human resource teams to organize information on each employee.
- Produced a server-rendered app that uses Express.js, MongoDB, and EJS to enable easy manipulation of data and the use of login authentication.
- Accomplished login authentication using sessions to enable bcrypt to hash passwords.

Space Battle - JQuery, HTML, CSS

- Design a browser -based game that allows the user to defeat aliens attacking Earth. The goal was to create a fun and interactive game between the user and the computer.
- Utilized JQuery to respond to user interactions and generate computer responses.
- Styled and created visual aspects using HTML5 and CSS3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wilderness Awareness School, Instructor | Seattle, WA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Led over 100+ kids in various age groups ranging from 6-12 years old through parks in Western Washington every week over the course of 3 months.
- Devised a curriculum each week focused on environmental protection, plant identification, and animal tracking that was tailored to each group.
- Dedicated each day to strategize a way to engage each student and fit the curriculum to each of their needs.

Coastal Plains Institute, Intern | Tallahassee, FL

August 2020 - April 2021

- Collected and analyzed data conducted on various field reports on ephemeral wetlands to restore and create a self-sustaining endangered species population in the Apalachicola National Forest.
- Optimized the social media platform to enhance awareness of the organization
- Implemented strategies to build a more involved volunteer community through optimizing the emails and social media.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

February 2022 - Present

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY | TALLAHASSEE, FL

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science

August 2018 - August 2021